In this video, we will learn how to make a uniform skirt.
First, open the button skirt and delete the extra panels.
Then we copy a belt panel, ctrl c, ctrl v, and put it in the 2D window.
Then we can make it a little longer. This length is the group length we made later.
Then we can activate this panel and right-click to reset the 2D arrangement position because its grid is broken.
Then we want to open this panel.
Before we open it, I want to show you how to make a uniform skirt.
First, I add two internal lines in the middle.
Then I will select one internal line and use the folding line here.
When the folding angle is 0, this line will protrude outward.
This protrusion means that it protrudes outward from the front of the panel.
If you can't see the front and back here, remember to switch to the texture surface to see the front and back of the panel.
On the contrary, if we set the folding angle to 360 degrees,
then this line will bend in from the front of the panel.
In order to make the panel fold more clearly, I will choose to print this panel.
When a panel is printed, all the internal lines on this panel,
the folding angle they apply, will be kept to the maximum extent.
In other words, it will fold more clearly.
After folding here, we will see that it will actually only have one-third of the width after folding.
So in order to make the panel we fold come out,
we need to make a panel that is three times wider.
After I delete the extra internal lines here,
we will start making the flat panel.
After selecting this panel, copy and paste, and then copy and paste.
There are three panels in total.
Then select the middle line and merge them.
After merging, delete the excess points.
Be sure to delete these points.
Next, we are going to merge the internal lines that are used to fold in the middle.
First, select the two-sided lines, then right-click and select the internal line generated according to the curve.
In the expansion number here, we need to select 3 times minus 1.
You can see that if my expansion number is 2, it can be cut into three sides.
So this value must be 3 times minus 1.
Here I set it to 20.
Then select the internal line created, right-click and select align.
Add points to the panel line.
Let's take a look at what happens if we don't select this step.
Because later we will use the function of folding and folding.
In the process of our sewing, it is identified as a group of three lines.
So we have to interrupt this line.
Then we select these internal lines, then right-click and select align.
Add points to the panel line.
After selecting, this will automatically be interrupted.
After interrupting, because we may have some stretching in the process of merging just now,
So in the 3D space, we reset the 2D arrangement position.
Then use the fold and fold function to press the left button on the first internal line.
On the right side of the last internal line, double-click, you can start to apply the fold angle.
This tool is used to automatically apply the fold angle.
First of all, we first choose the type to follow the fold.
This is the direction of the fold of the clothing group.
Then the internal line number of each fold is selected as 3.
Other options do not need to be changed.
Then click to confirm, you can see that the color of the internal line becomes red and green.
These fold angles are applied.
Don't rush to deny.
You can take a look.
If I go to sew directly,
Because the panel line will cross the human body.
Then in the process of sewing, plus the fold is left and right.
May be a little unstable.
So usually we will be in the 3D window.
First, the panel line is simulated.
Let it fold first.
Then we sew it to the belt.
After folding, we first rotate it to the side of the virtual model.
Then we repeat the fold angle.
Then we copy and paste a panel line.
Note that it is a copy and paste, not a copy and paste a clonical symmetrical panel.
Or copy and paste a mirror.
It's directly copied and pasted.
Because the direction of the line is one direction.
If you have a symmetrical panel line,
It's from the middle to the two sides to go along.
It's not the way of the clothing group.
Then we use the fold angle tool.
First, sew the waistband, and then click from the left side of the pleats.
Here is also, first sew the waistband, then click the starting point, along the mouse, and then click here at the end.
Then start to simulate, wait for the panel to simulate, that's it.
If the fold here is not very obvious after simulation, we can print the panel first.
After simulation, use the sewing machine to sew the front and back.
After the final completion, you can remove the hardening.
Now we can clearly see from the bottom that its folding direction will not change.
Then let's take a look at how to do it.
First, we need to modify the waistband.
First of all, many models will have a much wider waist than the waist.
So if we directly use the whole waist to make the skirt, the front looks very flat.
But the back here, because the hips are fuller, so the fold may expand.
Then let's see how to modify it.
In fact, the way to modify the waistband is a bit troublesome.
Because the waistband is piled up here on the waist.
If we stretch the waistband directly, there may be an interlocking problem.
So in most cases, we may do it again directly from the beginning.
So we have a lot of sewing lines that need to be deleted.
After that, repeat the operation as before,
but we need to stretch the waistband a little wider.
Do this a couple of times.
Now I have two pleats of seam
Then the waist is folded into the middle.
And then we can see that the strap of the waist is too high.
This means that if you do not stitch the waistband right from here,
the waist will not be comfortable.
Then the waist band is folded into the middle.
Let's try to do the same on the other side.
This is how it looks at one side.
So it is made like this.
And if you fold the sides of the waist,
you will have a very thin waistband.
Thank you.
You can see that when our board is wider, in fact, from the back, it does not have a very obvious problem of expansion.
Of course, in addition to this, you can also make this board into a arched board.
In order to prevent the board from transforming,
it is the same as the previous videos.
We can directly copy a fabric here,
and then increase the strength of the gold-plated sandpaper of this fabric,
or use Fusible Rigid.
In addition, we can also make it look more close to the physical properties on the top.
First, select the physical properties of this skirt part,
and then reduce the strength of the gold-plated sandpaper a little bit,
so that it will have a better hammering feeling.
Then reduce the bending strength a little bit,
so that it looks more soft.
Also, this is our particle diameter can be reduced a little bit.
When our particle diameter is reduced,
there is no small black spot caused by the gap in the network.
But here we will see that,
in fact, because the length of the board is not right,
so the skirt board at the bottom looks like there will be some wrinkles on the top.
If you want to smooth these wrinkles, it is also possible.
After polishing the surface,
we use the stabilizer to adjust the thermal resistance,
no matter how high is the thermal resistance to itself.
Then we will adjust the thermal resistance through the properties in the physical properties.
The formwork under the formwork editor has deformation rate.
The deformation rate is controlled by whether the fabric is easily deformed under the influence of external forces.
For example, the ferrous line is the most obvious example.
When the deformation rate is 100, the fold of the ferrous line position will be smoothed,
there will be no change in the shape of the fold.
Next, I will show you how to deal with some of the problems we encounter when we make the uniform.
First of all, when we make the uniform, we often encounter a problem,
that is, the plate, because it is folded,
so in the process of simulation, if the simulation is unstable,
sometimes it may happen that the part that should be folded should be folded in.
In the case of folding problems like this, we can adjust it with a fixed needle tool.
First of all, we can go back to the previous stabilization,
and see if we can manually adjust it to prevent such problems.
But if we fail to drag it out,
we can use a fixed needle to pull out the middle line.
First of all,
we can select this edge,
we can select a small piece of the fixed needle in the 2D window or the 3D window,
find its approximate position,
and then return to the time when the fixed needle was not created,
add a fixed needle along the edge of this hole,
and then move the fixed needle when there is no fire simulation in the 3D space.
When we start the simulation, the board will automatically fold,
then we can delete this fixed needle and simulate it.
Next, we can put it together,
use the fixed needle tool to sew the front middle and the back middle together.
After we start the simulation,
we will find that there are some shaking problems on the surface.
This is because our deformation intensity is 100.
In the process of recording some animation,
if it is not particularly obvious,
do not set the deformation rate to 100.
But it doesn't matter if we do the mirroring.
Then we can reduce the overall particle diameter to 5,
because we are going to delete the inner line later.
When the particle diameter is 5,
the overall computer operation speed will be slower.
At this time,
if we delete the inner line,
we can simulate it relatively slowly.
Double-click twice on an inner line,
you can select the inner line on the entire board.
Then we can delete these inner lines.
In the process,
we can double-click to simulate it briefly.
This simulation of the deformation will look softer.
Next, let's see what happens when the particle diameter is 15.
When the particle diameter is 15,
if we delete the inner line,
we can see that because the network is relatively small,
so if we simulate it,
first, its fold is easy to dissipate.
Second, its fold is not smooth.
In addition to the knife fold that we just demonstrated,
we also have a method of folding called the bow fold.
Here,
we can see that the angle of the fold is different.
its difference is just that
when we flip the paper,
we choose the middle option,
the bow fold.
Then let's take a look at the final effect of the fold.
After our hardening simulation,
we can see that this board is now folded like this,
and it has a groove and a protrusion.
Then we now put the board,
let's sew it up and take a look.
Here we can see that when we use the sewing paper tool,
its method is the same as that of the knife fold.
Just sew from left to right.
After sewing up,
we can see from its bottom that
it has a groove,
and there is a protruding structure.
When the angle of the fold is relatively low,
let's take a look at the final effect inside the book.
The final effect,
we can see that its structure is like a bow.
So this fold is called the bow fold.
So many second-dimensional clothes,
they are mostly bow or knife.
That is, when we sew them up,
Thank you.